

## CONTACT

**PHONE:** +34 644 380 004

EMAIL: <a href="mailto:hello@guillem.cat">hello@guillem.cat</a>

WEB: guillem.cat LinkedIn: gfernandezg GitHub: guillemf

HOME: Barcelona, Spain

## **SKILLS**

#### **AGILE PROJECT MANAGEMENT:**

Kanban, eXtreme Programming, CI/CD

**BUSINESS MANAGEMENT:** Budget definition, OKR, Delivery Strategy

**SOFTWARE DESIGN:** Architectures, Software Templates, DDD, TDD, BDD, DevOps

**PEOPLE MANAGEMENT:** Team Management, Hiring, Career Definition, Goal Settings

# **LANGUAGES**

Spanish, Catalan

Native

**English** 

C2

Francaise

A2

# Guillem Fernandez

# **Engineering Director**

I define myself as a **People Engineer**. I've been involved in IT Engineering since I left College. I've **founded** two companies, helped create two more from zero to success, and been involved in many other initiatives.

I am **teaching** at University of Barcelona because I love to share my experience. In general I love **challenges**.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Engineering Manager**

2020 - Present

BUMBLE / Barcelona, Spain

- Being part of the Friendship business line in Bumble, I am in charge of a team of engineers coming from different backgrounds.
- The goal in this position has been to create high performance and cohered teams, built on the concept of independence, good practices and commitment with the project.

CEO & Cofounder 2019-2020

CoKaiDo / Barcelona, Spain

- I founded this company in 2019. My role as CEO in this project was to drive the business to become the most successful company in expert and high-level training and help our clients to get ownership of the expertise and best practices.
- I created CoKaiDo as the central source of improvement for companies that wanted to go one step forward and build high performance teams.

### **Managing Director**

2016-2019

Codurance / Barcelona, Spain

- As a Managing Director I am responsible of running Barcelona Codurance's office, taking care of business operations and provide consultancy and training services to our clients.
- Our daily work is based in helping our customer to acquire the necessary skill to be able to work applying engineering best practices.

Senior Lead Developer - PaddyPower	2015-2016
Senior Lead Developer - Stella¨	2013-2015
Senior iOS Developer - Freelance	2012-2013
Mobile Team Lead - HostelWorld	2012-2012
Senior iOS Developer - ISIS Papyrus	2011-2012
CTO & HR Manager - Arestes	2009-2011
Business Manager - Alten TIC	2008-2009

# **EDUCATION**

ENGINEERING DEGREE in Software Engineering

1991 - 1996

Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya

**PROJECT MANAGEMENT** in PRINCE2 *Getronics Spain Solutions* 

2001